ALEXANDER LAMBROW

Software Developer

CONTACT ME:

(410) 206-7229 alexander.lambrow@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/alexander-lambrow/ github.com/alambrow

Projects

VIBEHUNT

(REACTJS, REACT-BOOTSTRAP)

Finding the right place to go out in the evening has again become an issue (thankfully). This app aggregates real-time data from the BestTime and Google Maps APIs to help users select the venues with the best vibe for an evening out and about in Nashville, TN.

github.com/alambrow/VibeHunt-ReactJS <URL of deployed site to go here>

SERVER-SIDE PROJECT (PYTHON, DJANGO)

More soon....

EDUCATION

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Apprenticeship
April 2021—September 2021

HARVARD UNIVERSITY

Ph.D. German Literature August 2013 — June 2019

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, BERKELEY

M.A. German Studies August 2011 — June 2013

DARTMOUTH COLLEGE

B.A. Comparative Literature (Phi Beta Kappa) September 2006 — June 2010

ABOUT

I am a humanities Ph.D. (German Literature) and former university lecturer who has transitioned into software development over the past year. I have been thrilled to see that the skills I developed in my first career—self-teaching, research, careful editing, and communication—translate well into the world of computer science. Ever since joining Nashville Software School as an apprentice this spring, I have been certain that this move is the right one for me.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | April 2021-September 2021

—Full-time software development bootcamp, with a focus on teaching full-stack fundamentals (Vanilla JavaScript, React, Python, Django) through self-guided project-based work.

APPLICATION MENTOR

Crimson Education | June 2019—present

- -Work on teams in university-admissions consulting, assisting high-school students apply to elite U.S. colleges
- -Specialize in the essay-writing process.

POSTDOCTORAL SCHOLAR/LECTURER

Vanderbilt University | August 2019—December 2020

- —Instructed five undergraduate-level courses in German language and cultural history
- —Conducted independent research in intellectual history, resulting in two articles and a book (forthcoming)

TEACHING FELLOW/LECTURER

Harvard University | August 2015-August 2018

- —Instructed twelve undergraduate-level courses in German language and cultural history
- -Presented research at twelve major international conferences (MLA, GSA)
- -Wrote and defended 50,000-word dissertation in intellectual history

SELECT PUBLICATIONS

"The Seriousness of Play: Johan Huizinga and Carl Schmitt on Play and the Political," *Games and Culture* 2020 (https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/abs/10.1177/1555412020975619)

"14 December 1930: Robert Musil Meets Carl Schmitt," *German Quarterly* 2017 (onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1111/gequ.12039)